Guide to the Rabbi Arthur Schneier Papers TAM.694
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III. Memberships and Affiliations, 1956-2014, undated; 5.77 Gigabytes in 83 computer files.; 13 Linear Feet in 27 manuscript boxes and 1 half manuscript box.
  - United States Alternate Representative to the 43rd Session of the United Nations General Assembly, 1988, undated; 1 folder (Box 260, Folder 21)
  - United States Commission for the Preservation of America's Heritage Abroad, 1986-1995, undated; 34 folders (Box 230, Folder 6, Box 125, Folder 16, 17, Box 150, Folder 12, Box 268, Folder 13, Box 176, Folder 3, Box 273, Folder 7, Box 187, Folder 1-17, Box 188, Folder 9, Box 189, Folder 3, 4, 9, 10, 23-25, Box 211, Folder 3, 4)
  - United States Institute of Peace, 1996-2006; 5 folders (Box 177, Folder 14, Box 283, Folder 31-34)
  - United States-Japan Foundation, 1980-1992, undated; 11 folders (Box 215, Folder 19, Box 89, Folder 18, Box 284, Folder 1-9)
  - Whitehead School Building Campaign Advisory Committee, 2007; 2 folders (Box 20, Folder 7, 8)
  - World Council of Religious Leaders, 2002, undated; 3 folders (Box 245, Folder 11, 12, Box 174, Folder 21)
  - World Jewish Congress, 1979-2014, undated; 23 folders (Box 242, Folder 18, Box 150, Folder 6, Box 159, Folder 22-30, Box 258, Folder 15, 16, Box 257, Folder 5, Box 181, Folder 29, Box 277, Folder 12, 22, Box 211, Folder 14-19)
  - World Jewish Leaders, 2006; 2 folders (Box 214, Folder 13, Box 188, Folder 4)
  - World Zionist Organization, 1997; 1 folder (Box 284, Folder 10)
- Series IV. Rabbi of Congregation B'nai Jacob and Park East Synagogue Records, 1942-2016, undated; 1965-2016; 2 audiocassettes; 6 film reels; 8.45 Gigabytes in 1,975 computer files.; 25 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 49 manuscript boxes, 5 half manuscript boxes, 1 small flat box, 2 oversize flat boxes, and 1 media box.
  This series contains material created over the course of Rabbi Arthur Schneier's work as a rabbi at Congregation B'nai Jacob and Park East Synagogue. The bulk of the material in this series are photographs of Rabbi Arthur Schneier in his vocation as a rabbi, correspondence between Rabbi Arthur Schneier and his congregants, issues of The Chronicle PES' newsletter, and press about Rabbi Arthur Schneier's work as a rabbi. Material in this series in includes audio cassette tapes, 16mm and 8mm films, correspondence, photographs, notes, menus, invitations, programs, schedules, speeches, publications, press, sermons, booklets, images, and video recordings. Of note are the photographs of Rabbi Arthur Schneier with Robert Kennedy, Mayor Wagner, and Judge Benjamin Glassman from 1965 and 16mm films of Schneier speaking at a Synagogue in Moscow, Soviet Union circa 1975, press and programs documenting Rabbi Schneier's move from Congregation B'nai Jacob to PES, and Rabbi Arthur Schneier's correspondence about the plight of Soviet Jews. There are born-digital media--image files--in this series.
  The material in this series is grouped by year, then arranged alphabetically by type.
  - Correspondence and Notes -- Schatten, Robert, 1942-1946, undated; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - 1950s-1960s Photographs, 1950-1969, undated; 5 folders (Box 238, Folder 16, 17, Box 111, Folder 14, 17, 21)
  - 1950s-1960s Photographs -- First Demonstration for Russia Jewry outside PES across from Soviet Embassy, 1950-1969; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 19)
  - 1950s-1960s Photographs -- Robert Kennedy, Mayor Wagner, and Judge Benjamin Glassman, 1950-1969; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder 18)
  - 1950s-1980s Photographs, TW_TAM_694_ER_19; 16.32 Megabytes in 37 computer files.
  - Photograph -- Yeshiva University Charter Anniversary Inaugural Dinner in Honor of Honorable Samuel Spayraegen, 1954; 1 folder (Box 113, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1957; 1 folder (Box 194, Folder 18)
  - Press and Correspondence -- Opening Prayers Delivered Before the House of Representatives, 1959-1964; 1 folder (Box 188, Folder 8)
  - Speeches and Notes, 1961-1983, undated; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Press -- Rabbi Arthur Schneier Leaves B'nai Jacob for PES, 1963; 1 folder (Box 284, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence -- Articles About Soviet Jews, 1964-1970; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1965; 1 folder (Box 157, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- The Council of Christians and Jews, 1965; 1 folder (Box 169, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence -- Israel, 1965; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 25)
  - Films -- Moscow Synagogue, circa 1965
    - Analog Recordings (Box 204, Film 694.0048, 694.0050, 694.0051)
    - Digital Recordings, TW_TAM_694_ER_101
  - Notes, 1965-1971; cuid2593; 3 folders (Box 157, Folder 1, Box 257, Folder 1, 2)
  - Press, 1965, undated; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 1)
  - Press -- PES Protest Plaque for Soviet Jews, 1965; 1 folder (Box 284, Folder 29)
  - Press -- Protest on Behalf of Soviet Jews, 1965; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Press -- Soviet Jews, 1965-1977; 1 folder (Box 202, Folder 7)
  - Press -- Visits to the Soviet Union, 1965-1975; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Article -- "Time Runs Out for Russia's Jews" in Look Magazine, 1966; 1 folder (Box 280, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1977; 2 folders (Box 194, Folder 10, Box 188, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence -- Responses to "Time Runs Out for Russia's Jews" in Look Magazine, 1966-1967; 2 folders (Box 280, Folder 18, 19)
  - Correspondence and ACF Committee Agendas, 1966-1977; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 19)
  - Press -- Article about Rabbi Arthur Schneier's Visit to Soviet Russia by Thurston Davis, SJ, 1966; 1 folder (Box 238, Folder 31)
  - Press -- Visits to the Soviet Union, 1966; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1967; 2 folders (Box 194, Folder 11, Box 256, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence -- Israel, 1967; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence -- Keating, Kenneth B., 1967-1976; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence and Press -- Yeshiva University, 1967-1981; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 2)
  - Press -- About Chaim Goldberg, 1967; 1 folder (Box 113, Folder 8)
  - Sermon Excerpts -- The Voice of Israel, 1967; 1 folder (Box 184, Folder 23)
  - Speeches, 1967-1985, undated; 1 folder (Box 192, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1968; 2 folders (Box 194, Folder 12, Box 256, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence -- Israel, 1968; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence -- About Look Magazine Article, A Bridge to Russia's Jews, 1968-1969; 1 folder (Box 162, Folder 2)
  - Photographs -- Jewish Religious Community of Moscow Choral Synagogue 1968, 1968, undated; 2 folders (Box 238, Folder 19, 22)
  - Press, 1968-1977; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Press and Correspondence, 1968-1984; 1 folder (Box 188, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1969; 2 folders (Box 194, Folder 13, Box 157, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence -- Central Board of Hungarian Jews, 1969-1981; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Photographs, and Press -- Soviet Rabbinical Students, 1969-1978, undated; 1 folder (Box 162, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and Press -- Israel, 1969; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence and Press -- Mosler, John, 1969-1971, undated; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Press and Postcards, 1969, undated; 1 folder (Box 229, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1970; 2 folders (Box 194, Folder 16, Box 258, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- Grace, Peter, 1970; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence -- Israel, 1970; 1 folder (Box 234, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence -- Romania, 1970-1973; 1 folder (Box 161, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence -- Romania and Soviet Jews, 1970; 1 folder (Box 161, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence -- Soviet Jewry, 1970-1979, undated; 5 folders (Box 76, Folder 2-5, Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence and Press -- Rogers, William P., 1970-1972; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 8)
  - Photograph -- With Kurt Waldheim, 1970s; 1 folder (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - Articles and Brochures -- Soviet Jewry, 1971-1978; 2 folders (Box 77, Folder 14, 15)
  - Correspondence, 1971, undated; 2 folders (Box 194, Folder 5, Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence -- The David Susskind Show WNEW-TV, 1971; 1 folder (Box 258, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- Prominent Business, Religious, and Political Leaders, 1971-1982; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and Notes -- Soviet Jewry, 1971, undated; 1 folder (Box 256, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence and Photograph, 1971; 1 folder (Box 258, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and Press -- Israel, 1971; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence and Programs -- Iakovos, Archbishop, 1971-1979; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Press, 1971; 1 folder (Box 208, Folder 23)
  - Transcribed Presentation to Rabbinical Council of America, 1971; 1 folder (Box 182, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1972; 1 folder (Box 194, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1975, undated; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence -- Kaplan, Armand, 1972-1977; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence -- Schatten, Robert, 1972; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- Terner, Emanuel, 1972-1978; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence -- Travel Information for Venezuela, 1972; 1 folder (Box 162, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and Itinerary -- Romanian Exchange Students, 1972; 1 folder (Box 161, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and Press -- Israel, 1972; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence -- Religious Heritage of America Award Nomination, 1973; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- Russian Articles on Jewish Community, 1973-1975; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Programs, and Press -- Romania, 1973-1978, undated; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence and Press -- Israel, 1973; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence and Press -- Richardson, Elliot L., 1973-1975; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and Press -- Soviet Rabbinic Students Studying in the United States, 1973-1976, undated; 1 folder (Box 258, Folder 8)
  - Negatives and Slides, 1973; 1 folder (Box 249, Folder 5)
  - Photographs -- Schneier, Rabbi Arthur, 1973, undated; 1 folder (Box 252, Folder 2)
  - Press -- Israel, 1973, undated; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1974; 1 folder (Box 194, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence -- Greek Orthodox Church, 1974-1975; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence -- Soviet Jewry, 1974-1992, undated; 2 folders (Box 77, Folder 2, 3)
  - Correspondence -- Wilson, Governor Malcolm of New York, 1974; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and Notes -- Levitt, William J., 1974-1976, undated; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence and Press -- Israel, 1974; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 23)
  - Notes -- Israel, 1974-1978; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - Press, 1974-1988; 1 folder (Box 284, Folder 37)
  - Program -- A Salute to Javitz, 1974; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1975; 2 folders (Box 238, Folder 18, Box 194, Folder 15)
  - Press -- Minskoff Cultural Center Construction, 1975; 1 folder (Box 284, Folder 40)
  - Booklet and List of Hotels -- Democratic National Convention in New York City, 1976; 1-11 folder (Box 162, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1976; 1 folder (Box 194, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence -- Associated YM-YWHAs of Greater New York, 1976; 1 folder (Box 258, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- International Requests for Aid, 1976-1977; 1 folder (Box 260, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence -- Invitations, 1976-1978; 1 folder (Box 165, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- Kenneth B. Keating Institute of American Studies Tel Aviv University, 1976-1977; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence -- Moscow Patriarchate, 1976; 1 folder (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence -- Scranton, William W., 1976; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence -- Titov, Victor, 1976-1977; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 16)
  - Photographs -- Chief Rabbi of Romania Rabbi Moshe Rosen accepts Torah Scroll Donated by Rabbi Arthur Schneier and Appeal of Conscience Foundation in Honor of his Anniversary, 1976-1977; 1 folder (Box 238, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1977; 1 folder (Box 194, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence -- Criminal Justice Legislation, 1977; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence -- Invitations, 1977-1980; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- Schatten, Robert, 1977; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- von Blomberg, Baron Frary, 1977-1978; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence -- Winter Holiday Messages, 1977, undated; 1 folder (Box 283, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Photograph, and Press -- Ceausescu, President Nicolae of Romania, 1977-1983, undated; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence and Press -- Israel, 1977-1994; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence and Speeches -- Soviet Jews, 1977, undated; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 11)
  - Notes, 1977; 1 folder (Box 259, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1978; 3 folders (Box 194, Folder 1, 2, Box 165, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence -- Israel, 1978; 1 folder (Box 234, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- National Committee on American Foreign Policy, INC., 1978-1979; 1 folder (Box 165, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence -- Schatten, Robert, 1978; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence -- United States Civil Rights Commission, 1978; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Menu, and Notes, 1978-1979, undated; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and Notes, 1978-1979, undated; 1 folder (Box 165, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence and Press, 1978-1979; 1 folder (Box 259, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, Programs, Invocation, and Guest List -- Koch, Mayor Edward I. of New York City, 1978-1981, undated; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 22)
  - Dinner in Honor of Margaret Thatcher List of Guests, 1978; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Itinerary -- Washington, D.C. and California, 1978; 1 folder (Box 259, Folder 5)
  - Notes -- 57 Armenians in the Netherlands, 1978; 1 folder (Box 165, Folder 15)
  - Press, 1978-1979; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Programs and Guest Lists, 1978-1981; 1 folder (Box 268, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1979; 3 folders (Box 194, Folder 7, Box 284, Folder 32, 35)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1994, undated; 1 folder (Box 284, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence -- Canadians, 1979-2014; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence -- The Martin Luther King, Jr. Center for Social Change, 1979; 1 folder (Box 160, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- Sanford Werfel Studios, 1979; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence -- Schatten, Robert, 1979; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence -- Soviet Rabbinical Students, 1979; 2 folders (Box 77, Folder 1, 6)
  - Negatives, 1979, undated; 1 folder (Box 249, Folder 11)
  - Press -- Schneier, Rabbi Arthur with West Germany's Chancellor Helmut Schmidt and Jacques Torczyner, 1979, undated; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 5)
  - Press -- Visits to Hungary, 1979-1987; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Proposal Drafts, 1979-1982; 1 folder (Box 260, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1981; 4 folders (Box 10, Folder 1, Box 194, Folder 8, Box 260, Folder 11, Box 284, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence -- Invitations to Events, 1980-1990; 1 folder (Box 267, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- Schatten, Robert, 1980; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Press, 1980-1997, undated; 1 folder (Box 166, Folder 20)
  - Speech -- United Nations Conference on The Arms Race and the Human Race, 1980; 1 folder (Box 277, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1981; 2 folders (Box 236, Folder 16, Box 194, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence -- About the Holocaust, 1981-1982; 1 folder (Box 281, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- International Center for University Teaching of Jewish Civilization, 1981-1989; 1 folder (Box 225, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence -- Schatten, Robert, 1981; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Lists of Dinner Party Guests, 1981; 1 folder (Box 194, Folder 21)
  - Press, 1981-1986; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1982; 4 folders (Box 229, Folder 3, Box 194, Folder 6, Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Flyer -- Yeshiva University International Affairs Institute A World Perspective, 1982; 1 folder (Box 264, Folder 17)
  - Invitation and Notes -- Rabbi and Mrs. Arthur Schneier Host Meeting with Mayor Ed Koch, 1982, undated; 1 folder (Box 259, Folder 10)
  - Photographs -- Schneier, Rabbi Arthur with Rabbi Soloveichik, 1982; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 17)
  - Register Supplements -- New York City Commission for the United Nations and for the Consular Corps, 1982; 1 folder (Box 259, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1983; 1 folder (Box 250, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1984; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence -- Gropman, Donald, 1983; 1 folder (Box 260, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence -- Invitations, 1983; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- Schneier, Rabbi Arthur and Donna Schneier's 25th Wedding Anniversary, 1983; 1 folder (Box 194, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence -- Schneier, Rabbi Arthur Letters of Recommendation for Jefferson Award from American Institute for Public Service, 1983-1984; 1 folder (Box 166, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence -- Yeshiva University, 1983; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 31)
  - Information Packet -- Welcome to the American Embassy Bucharest, 1983-1986; 1 folder (Box 230, Folder 8)
  - Notes, 1983-1985, undated; 1 folder (Box 252, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1983; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 23)
  - Press -- Pope John Paul II Meets with Rabbi Arthur Schneier, 1983; 1 folder (Box 188, Folder 2)
  - Article, 1984; 1 folder (Box 277, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1984; 4 folders (Box 10, Folder 3, Box 215, Folder 6, Box 171, Folder 17, Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence -- Chinese Scholars, 1984-1989; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence -- Chinese Scholars and Ambassadors, 1984-1989; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- Condolence Messages, 1984-1985; 1 folder (Box 159, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence -- Dorn and Coffinas, 1984; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- O'Hare, President Joseph A., S.J. of Fordham University, 1984; 1 folder (Box 170, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- Appearance on NBC News Program, 1984; 1 folder (Box 159, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1985; 3 folders (Box 10, Folder 4, Box 260, Folder 15, Box 282, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence -- Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe, 1985-1987; 2 folders (Box 160, Folder 6, 7)
  - Correspondence -- Declined Invitations to Events, 1985-1990; 1 folder (Box 267, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence -- Invitations, 1985; 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence -- Requests for Help, 1985; 1 folder (Box 268, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence -- Romanian Bibles, 1985; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- The White House, 1985; 1 folder (Box 166, Folder 21)
  - Speech -- The National Press Club, 1985; 1 folder (Box 277, Folder 7)
  - Speech -- About Louis Farrakhan, 1985; 1 folder (Box 277, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, Press, and Invitation, 1985; 1 folder (Box 277, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1986; 3 folders (Box 10, Folder 5, Box 9, Folder 10, 21)
  - Correspondence -- Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe, 1986; 1 folder (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- Davis, Father Thurston Funeral, 1986; 1 folder (Box 159, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence -- Grass, Martin L., 1986; 1 folder (Box 159, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence -- Invitations, 1986, undated; 2 folders (Box 10, Folder 6, Box 171, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence -- Lauder, Ambassador Ronald, 1986; 1 folder (Box 159, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence -- Requests for Help, 1986; 1 folder (Box 268, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence -- Soviet Ambassador Konstantin Kharchev's Visit to the United States, 1986; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- United Nations Association Minnesota, 1986; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence and Handout -- The Mens Club of PES, 1986; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and Press, 1986; 1 folder (Box 282, Folder 6)
  - Press and Correspondence -- Lord Weidenfeld at PES, 1986-1988; 1 folder (Box 188, Folder 1)
  - Programs -- City of New York Inaugural Ceremonies, 1986; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Speech -- New York City Mayoral Inauguration, 1986; 1 folder (Box 277, Folder 6)
  - Speeches, 1986-1989; 2 folders (Box 192, Folder 10, Box 277, Folder 5)
  - Biographical Information and Press, 1987-1995, undated; 1 folder (Box 166, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1987; 5 folders (Box 10, Folder 7, Box 171, Folder 9, 18, Box 9, Folder 20, Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1988; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence -- Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe, 1987; 1 folder (Box 160, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence -- Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe Plenary Meeting Statements and Reports, 1987; 1 folder (Box 160, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- Invitations, 1987; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- Invitations to Events, 1987; 1 folder (Box 266, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence -- Regarding Lorant Sallay's Visa Request, 1987; 1 folder (Box 159, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence -- Requests for Help, 1987; 1 folder (Box 268, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- Sasakawa, Yohei, 1987-1988; 1 folder (Box 225, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Notes, and Travel Information -- Sasakawa, Ryoichi, 1987, undated; 1 folder (Box 227, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and Travel Information -- Sasakawa, Ryoichi, 1987; 2 folders (Box 225, Folder 20, 21)
  - Interview -- The Man and His Mission, 1987; 1 folder (Box 184, Folder 26)
  - Press -- The Congressional Record, 1987; 1 folder (Box 276, Folder 14)
  - Press -- Remarks in the Congressional Record, 1987; 1 folder (Box 159, Folder 20)
  - Program -- The International League for the Repatriation of Russian Jews Awards Dinner, 1987; 1 folder (Box 268, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1988; 3 folders (Box 10, Folder 9, 10, Box 171, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence -- 25th Anniversary as Rabbi of PES Congratulatory Messages, 1988; 1 folder (Box 166, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence -- 40th Anniversary of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, 1988; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence -- About the Jewish Chinese Community, 1988, undated; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence -- Federal U.S. Government Officials, 1988; 1 folder (Box 160, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- Government Officials, 1988-1989; 1 folder (Box 268, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence -- Invitations, 1988; 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence -- Invitations to Events, 1988; 2 folders (Box 266, Folder 13, Box 267, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- Letters of Recommendation for Rabbi Schneier as Assistant Secretary of State for Human Rights and Humanitarian Affairs, 1988, undated; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence -- Letters of Recommendation for Rabbi Schneier to Receive the Presidential Medal of Freedom, 1988-1990; 1 folder (Box 261, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence -- The Presidential Trust, 1988, undated; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence -- Republican Party Members, 1988; 1 folder (Box 268, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence -- Requests for Help, 1988; 1 folder (Box 268, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence -- Winter Holiday Cards, 1988; 2 folders (Box 171, Folder 19, Box 268, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- Winter Holiday Messages, 1988; 1 folder (Box 268, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and Press -- The White House, 1988-1992; 1 folder (Box 189, Folder 16)
  - Invocation, 1988; 1 folder (Box 277, Folder 17)
  - Press -- PES Man of the Year Louis M. Perlman, 1988; 1 folder (Box 277, Folder 35)
  - Programs -- Annual Dinner Sheriff's Jury, Inc., 1988; 1 folder (Box 211, Folder 11)
  - Speech -- Millennium of the Russian Orthodox Church by: Rabbi Arthur Schneier, 1988; 2 folders (Box 182, Folder 4, Box 181, Folder 31)
  - Speech, 1988; 1 folder (Box 276, Folder 13)